<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Peter McConnell</title>
    <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Peter McConnell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:36:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petermcconnell.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux performance ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/binary_perf_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/binary_perf_summary/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing the Performance of your Linux Binaries When it comes to software performance, every little bit counts. This is especially true for Linux binaries, which are often used in resource-constrained environments or where every millisecond of performance matters. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some tips for optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries.
Tip 1: Use a high-performance compiler The first step to optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries is to use a high-performance compiler.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimizing-the-performance-of-your-linux-binaries&#34;&gt;Optimizing the Performance of your Linux Binaries&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to software performance, every little bit counts. This is especially true for Linux binaries, which are often used in resource-constrained environments or where every millisecond of performance matters. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some tips for optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1-use-a-high-performance-compiler&#34;&gt;Tip 1: Use a high-performance compiler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step to optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries is to use a high-performance compiler. Modern compilers like GCC and Clang have various optimization flags that can significantly improve the performance of your code. For example, the &amp;ldquo;-O2&amp;rdquo; flag enables a variety of optimization techniques that can improve the performance of your code, while the &amp;ldquo;-Ofast&amp;rdquo; flag enables even more aggressive optimizations that can further improve performance but may result in code that is less standards-compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2-use-a-faster-runtime&#34;&gt;Tip 2: Use a faster runtime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The runtime environment of your Linux binary can also have a significant impact on its performance. For example, using a faster interpreter or just-in-time (JIT) compiler can improve the performance of interpreted or JIT-compiled languages like Python, JavaScript, and Java. You can also consider using a faster garbage collector to reduce the overhead of memory management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-3-optimize-your-algorithms-and-data-structures&#34;&gt;Tip 3: Optimize your algorithms and data structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithms and data structures you use can also have a big impact on the performance of your Linux binaries. Choosing the right algorithm and data structure for the task at hand can significantly improve the performance of your code. For example, using a hash table instead of a linked list for lookups can greatly improve the performance of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-4-use-profiling-tools&#34;&gt;Tip 4: Use profiling tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profiling tools can help you identify areas of your code that are causing performance bottlenecks. For example, you can use tools like perf, Valgrind, and gprof to measure the performance of your code and identify areas that could be optimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-5-use-a-performance-tuned-linux-distribution&#34;&gt;Tip 5: Use a performance-tuned Linux distribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, using a performance-tuned Linux distribution can also improve the performance of your Linux binaries. Distributions like Arch Linux and Gentoo are known for their focus on performance and can provide a lightweight and optimized environment for your applications to run in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries requires a combination of tools and techniques. By using a high-performance compiler, a faster runtime, optimizing your algorithms and data structures, using profiling tools, and using a performance-tuned Linux distribution, you can significantly improve the performance of your Linux binaries and deliver better results to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/current-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/current-reading/</guid>
      <description>The Linux Programming Interface I should have read this years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a big boi, but if you work around linux or are interested in it - this book is a critical primer on many of the core topics you&amp;rsquo;ll need to really understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on. I binged this book on the first pass over multiple weeks - deliberately skipping implementing the code examples, opting to just read them / ensure I understood them.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-linux-programming-interface&#34;&gt;The Linux Programming Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have read this years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a big boi, but if you work around linux
or are interested in it - this book is a critical primer on many of the core
topics you&amp;rsquo;ll need to really understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on. I binged this book on
the first pass over multiple weeks - deliberately skipping implementing the
code examples, opting to just read them / ensure I understood them. I choose to
do this so that I could get over as much content as possible, with the view of
circling back over the examples once I&amp;rsquo;m finished The C Programming Language
book so that I can make better decisions about the code I&amp;rsquo;m writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s.cdnshm.com/catalog/pt/t/33820519/linux-programming-interface.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Buy it&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Programming-Interface-System-Handbook/dp/1593272200&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Programming-Interface-System-Handbook/dp/1593272200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-c-programming-language&#34;&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally try to avoid taking on multiple books but I figured as the above is
so large and much of the books example code is given in C, then this book which
I&amp;rsquo;m long overdue on would be a nice complement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fine. Concise and clear wording; unlike the print quality, unfortunately.
This books print looks like it was hand-painted by a very nervous individual trying
to hit a deadline in the dark. Print-quality aside, I&amp;rsquo;d say this is an
important book to read, but not much of a page-turner. For me the biggest
advantage of the book was seeing syscall libraries in action and also
appreciating more about what cpp gives us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/C1bOAdsnZnS._CR504,0,3024,3024_UX256.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Buy it&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/C-Programming-Language-2nd/dp/0131103628&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/C-Programming-Language-2nd/dp/0131103628&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;up-next&#34;&gt;Up next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two &amp;ldquo;crackers&amp;rdquo; on my desk. Really looking forward to these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel Development (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Kernel-Development-Developers-Library/dp/0672329468&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Kernel-Development-Developers-Library/dp/0672329468&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Performance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Systems-Performance-Brendan-Gregg/dp/0136820158&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Systems-Performance-Brendan-Gregg/dp/0136820158&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
