<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>perf on Peter McConnell</title>
    <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/tags/perf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in perf on Peter McConnell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:36:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petermcconnell.com/tags/perf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux performance ideas</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/binary_perf_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/binary_perf_summary/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing the Performance of your Linux Binaries When it comes to software performance, every little bit counts. This is especially true for Linux binaries, which are often used in resource-constrained environments or where every millisecond of performance matters. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some tips for optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries.
Tip 1: Use a high-performance compiler The first step to optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries is to use a high-performance compiler.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimizing-the-performance-of-your-linux-binaries&#34;&gt;Optimizing the Performance of your Linux Binaries&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to software performance, every little bit counts. This is especially true for Linux binaries, which are often used in resource-constrained environments or where every millisecond of performance matters. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some tips for optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1-use-a-high-performance-compiler&#34;&gt;Tip 1: Use a high-performance compiler&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step to optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries is to use a high-performance compiler. Modern compilers like GCC and Clang have various optimization flags that can significantly improve the performance of your code. For example, the &amp;ldquo;-O2&amp;rdquo; flag enables a variety of optimization techniques that can improve the performance of your code, while the &amp;ldquo;-Ofast&amp;rdquo; flag enables even more aggressive optimizations that can further improve performance but may result in code that is less standards-compliant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2-use-a-faster-runtime&#34;&gt;Tip 2: Use a faster runtime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The runtime environment of your Linux binary can also have a significant impact on its performance. For example, using a faster interpreter or just-in-time (JIT) compiler can improve the performance of interpreted or JIT-compiled languages like Python, JavaScript, and Java. You can also consider using a faster garbage collector to reduce the overhead of memory management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-3-optimize-your-algorithms-and-data-structures&#34;&gt;Tip 3: Optimize your algorithms and data structures&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithms and data structures you use can also have a big impact on the performance of your Linux binaries. Choosing the right algorithm and data structure for the task at hand can significantly improve the performance of your code. For example, using a hash table instead of a linked list for lookups can greatly improve the performance of your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-4-use-profiling-tools&#34;&gt;Tip 4: Use profiling tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profiling tools can help you identify areas of your code that are causing performance bottlenecks. For example, you can use tools like perf, Valgrind, and gprof to measure the performance of your code and identify areas that could be optimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-5-use-a-performance-tuned-linux-distribution&#34;&gt;Tip 5: Use a performance-tuned Linux distribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, using a performance-tuned Linux distribution can also improve the performance of your Linux binaries. Distributions like Arch Linux and Gentoo are known for their focus on performance and can provide a lightweight and optimized environment for your applications to run in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimizing the performance of your Linux binaries requires a combination of tools and techniques. By using a high-performance compiler, a faster runtime, optimizing your algorithms and data structures, using profiling tools, and using a performance-tuned Linux distribution, you can significantly improve the performance of your Linux binaries and deliver better results to your users.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>website perf - a few common performance improvement ideas for web applications</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/website_perf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/website_perf/</guid>
      <description>5 Tips for Improving the Performance of your Web Applications Performance is critical to the success of any application. Poor performance can lead to a poor user experience, reduced engagement, and ultimately, decreased revenue. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore five tips for improving the performance of your applications.
Tip 1: Measure and monitor performance regularly The first step to improving performance is understanding where the bottlenecks are. To do this, you need to measure and monitor performance regularly.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-tips-for-improving-the-performance-of-your-web-applications&#34;&gt;5 Tips for Improving the Performance of your Web Applications&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance is critical to the success of any application. Poor performance can lead to a poor user experience, reduced engagement, and ultimately, decreased revenue. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore five tips for improving the performance of your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1-measure-and-monitor-performance-regularly&#34;&gt;Tip 1: Measure and monitor performance regularly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step to improving performance is understanding where the bottlenecks are. To do this, you need to measure and monitor performance regularly. Use tools like profilers, load testers, and monitoring tools to gather data on the performance of your application. This will help you identify areas that are causing slowdowns and prioritize improvements. Setting up a visualisation tool for this, such as Grafana, will mean that you can get this data whenever you need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2-optimize-database-queries&#34;&gt;Tip 2: Optimize database queries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Databases are often a major source of performance issues. To optimize database queries, consider using indexing to speed up query execution, use caching to store frequently accessed data, and use explain plans to understand how queries are being executed. You should also consider using a database optimization tool to identify and fix common issues. You should ensure your query caching stragegy is sound for your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-3-use-a-cdn-for-static-content&#34;&gt;Tip 3: Use a CDN for static content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) are a great way to improve the performance of your application. CDNs store static content like images, CSS, and JavaScript on servers around the world, so that users can access them from a location that is closer to them. This can significantly reduce the time it takes for static content to load, resulting in a faster overall page load time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-4-optimize-front-end-performance&#34;&gt;Tip 4: Optimize front-end performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front-end of your application plays a critical role in performance. To optimize front-end performance, consider using techniques like minification, compression, and lazy loading. You should also consider using a tool like Webpack to bundle and optimize your assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-5-use-a-load-balancer&#34;&gt;Tip 5: Use a load balancer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a high traffic application, using a load balancer can help distribute traffic across multiple servers, which can improve the performance of your application. Load balancers can also help improve the reliability of your application by automatically routing traffic away from overloaded servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improving the performance of your application requires a combination of tools and techniques. By regularly measuring and monitoring performance, optimizing database queries, using a CDN for static content, optimizing front-end performance, and using a load balancer, you can significantly improve the performance of your application and provide a better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
