<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peter McConnell</title>
    <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Peter McConnell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:30:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.petermcconnell.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:54:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/skills/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dL6kQ0v1PQ8
I&amp;rsquo;m a solid debugger, reasonable systems designer &amp;amp; natural leader. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with enough talent to know I&amp;rsquo;m nothing special; but I have a great track record for being good to work with and getting shit done be it as an IC, a manager, or a group lead.
Usually never far from:
Python Golang Bash Linux Docker Kubernetes AWS Over 20 years I&amp;rsquo;ve touched a lot of different tech and generally speaking can shake the rust off or learn something new in a week or two.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dL6kQ0v1PQ8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dL6kQ0v1PQ8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a solid debugger, reasonable systems designer &amp;amp; natural leader. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked
with enough talent to know I&amp;rsquo;m nothing special; but I have a great track record
for being good to work with and getting shit done be it as an IC, a manager,
or a group lead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually never far from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Golang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 20 years I&amp;rsquo;ve touched a lot of different tech and generally speaking can
shake the rust off or learn something new in a week or two.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/showcase/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a while and done some things. Even some good things.
helped take two companies to acquisition developed a custom query language (TQL - an opencypher variant) which went to market [ Java. Golang. ANTLR ] added support into the Terraform AWS provider for shipping your own keys to ACM [ Golang ] developed an orchestration framework for researchers in AI to schedule workloads [ Python. Terraform. AWS.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a while and done some things. Even some good things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;helped take two companies to acquisition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed a custom query language (TQL - an opencypher variant) which went to market
[ Java. Golang. ANTLR ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added support into the Terraform AWS provider for shipping your own keys to ACM
[ Golang ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed an orchestration framework for researchers in AI to schedule workloads
[ Python. Terraform. AWS. On-prem (Nvidia DGX&amp;rsquo;s). Qemu. Libvirt ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customised redhat&amp;rsquo;s clair product so that it could use internal sources for its vulnerability databases
[ Golang ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed a compliance tool which detects packages for Python, Ruby, R, APT, Yum, APK and assesses their licenses
[ Shell ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed a chatbot which used a large car forum database, bayes theorum and more regular expressions than you can shake a stick at to allow users to talk to cars. in 3 weeks!
[ PHP, Postgres ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built a security tool &amp;ldquo;amald&amp;rdquo; which alerts on the event that an endpoint is without authentication. decreased companies time-to-detection for auth misconfigurations
[ Golang ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed an image delivery service for a very large org (30k+ engineers)
[ AWS, Python, Bash/Shell, OpenStack ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have worked on web products for Google, Virgin, Red Bull, Disney &amp;amp; YouTube
[ Python. PHP. During my time as a lead at https://www.rehabagency.ai/work ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;design and build out of various deployment infrastructure
[ Kubernetes. Mesos. Marathon. Docker-compose. ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;developed a Jira plugin which extended JQL (jira query language) to allow grouping by &amp;ldquo;roles&amp;rdquo;
[ Java ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;competed in various hackathons and code jams
[ Hacktoberfest, Ludum Dare, Google CTF ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mentored many amazing engineers over the years from Junior to Staff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spoken at various conferences in the UK, Ireland, Australia and the U.S on docker, prometheus, bash, terraform, aws etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;co-founded an award winning web design company (31interactive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 years working in tech and the above is all the &amp;ldquo;good things&amp;rdquo; I can think of
listing. Imagine how long the &amp;ldquo;bad things&amp;rdquo; list must be ..&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/about/</guid>
      <description>$PATH When I was around 9 through some miracle mum brought home a Commodore Amiga. My family never had much growing up but somehow we still got a computer. Little did she know at the time just how big an impact that would have on my life - thanks Mum. I gorged on all the Warez I could get my hands slowly increasing my exposure to programming and hacking. The culture has always felt like home.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;path&#34;&gt;$PATH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was around 9 through some miracle mum brought home a Commodore Amiga.
My family never had much growing up but somehow we still got a computer. Little
did she know at the time just how big an impact that would have on my life -
thanks Mum. I gorged on all the Warez I could get my hands slowly increasing
my exposure to programming and hacking. The culture has always felt like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I had to earn money and knew working with computers was something I
had to do - any other job would feel like work and I didn&amp;rsquo;t much like work. So
with some luck and a sprinkle of white-lies I landed my first web developer
role around 2004 and was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward some years, I&amp;rsquo;m currently posted at firebolt.io where I help
several teams who are focused around automation and running infrastructure. We
have many complex problems to solve but the progress we&amp;rsquo;re making is truly
amazing. Oblig. &amp;ldquo;My views are my own / not representative of my employer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of work I try to contribute to the community when I can, though spare
time is expensive when you have kids to spend it on. I recently got to speak at
NIDC though which was nice - you can catch it here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvtZnbDXpzM&amp;amp;t=20063s&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvtZnbDXpzM&amp;amp;t=20063s&lt;/a&gt;. And indeed, that is a
Final Fantasy VII t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal focus has shifted towards performance and systems engineering lately.
In particular, pulling more information out of the kernel to help developers
debug interesting issues is a fascinating topic I&amp;rsquo;m spending more time on. The
problem is, with such tools to hand life seemingly becomes an endless longing
for a process to spin out of control with not a reasonable error in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for me you can find me on Twitter (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/&lt;/a&gt;) or
Github (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/peter-mcconnell)&#34;&gt;https://github.com/peter-mcconnell)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun trinkets from along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amiga_500&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amiga_500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chaos_Engine&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chaos_Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burn_Cycle&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burn_Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macromedia_Flash&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macromedia_Flash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackers_(film)&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackers_(film)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAI8S2houW4&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OAI8S2houW4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/current-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 20:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.petermcconnell.com/posts/current-reading/</guid>
      <description>The Linux Programming Interface I should have read this years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a big boi, but if you work around linux or are interested in it - this book is a critical primer on many of the core topics you&amp;rsquo;ll need to really understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on. I binged this book on the first pass over multiple weeks - deliberately skipping implementing the code examples, opting to just read them / ensure I understood them.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-linux-programming-interface&#34;&gt;The Linux Programming Interface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have read this years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a big boi, but if you work around linux
or are interested in it - this book is a critical primer on many of the core
topics you&amp;rsquo;ll need to really understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on. I binged this book on
the first pass over multiple weeks - deliberately skipping implementing the
code examples, opting to just read them / ensure I understood them. I choose to
do this so that I could get over as much content as possible, with the view of
circling back over the examples once I&amp;rsquo;m finished The C Programming Language
book so that I can make better decisions about the code I&amp;rsquo;m writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s.cdnshm.com/catalog/pt/t/33820519/linux-programming-interface.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Buy it&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Programming-Interface-System-Handbook/dp/1593272200&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Programming-Interface-System-Handbook/dp/1593272200&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-c-programming-language&#34;&gt;The C Programming Language&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally try to avoid taking on multiple books but I figured as the above is
so large and much of the books example code is given in C, then this book which
I&amp;rsquo;m long overdue on would be a nice complement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fine. Concise and clear wording. Unlike the print quality, unfortunately.
This book looks like it was hand-painted by a very nervous individual trying
to hit a deadline, in the dark. I&amp;rsquo;d say this is an important book, but not much
of a page-turned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/C1bOAdsnZnS._CR504,0,3024,3024_UX256.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;Buy it&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/C-Programming-Language-2nd/dp/0131103628&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/C-Programming-Language-2nd/dp/0131103628&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;up-next&#34;&gt;Up next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two &amp;ldquo;crackers&amp;rdquo; on my desk. Really looking forward to these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux Kernel Development (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Kernel-Development-Developers-Library/dp/0672329468&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Linux-Kernel-Development-Developers-Library/dp/0672329468&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Performance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Systems-Performance-Brendan-Gregg/dp/0136820158&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Systems-Performance-Brendan-Gregg/dp/0136820158&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
